Hello English learners.
Welcome back to English pod.
My name is Marko and I'm Erica.
And today we have another
romantic lesson, kind of romantic.
A little romantic. We
got a boyfriend and a
girlfriend and they're
apologizing to each other.
Okay, so it's a very common situation
and we're going to be talking about love.
We're also going to
talk about different
pet names that are
commonly used in English.
That are used with your
boyfriend or girlfriend.
Okay, very good. So, let's
listen to this dialogue for
the first time and see what's
happening with her couple.
Can we talk? Sure, honey.
We're talking now, aren't we?
You know what I
mean. Yeah, I know.
I want to know where
this relationship is going.
I mean, love with you
and I need to know.
You know, I think you're
awesome. I'm awesome.
Well, I guess that's my
answer, isn't it? Honey.
Look, if you don't love
me, it's not a thing, all right?
We've had our laughs,
but I don't appreciate, well,
maybe it's just time we...
Baby, I love you so much.
You do? I love you and
I think you're awesome.
Oh, I love you too. Come on, put
the gun down. Oh, baby, I'm so sorry.
Okay, so romantic and dramatic.
Yeah, I think she really
needed to hear that, right?
So I think she really wanted
to hear that I love you.
Yeah, that's right. And
there's some interesting
phrases here in this
dialogue. And today we're
going to focus mostly on
phrases. So why don't we
start with fluency
builder? Fluency builder.
Okay, on fluency builder
today, we are going to take
a look at some of these
phrases. And the first
one is very important
and very different.
So obviously this dialogue
is about love and we
heard two different ways
that this word is used.
And the first one
is to love someone.
Right, so he said, I love
you. Yeah, I love you.
We all pretty much
understand what that means.
Right, but they also mentioned
to be in love with someone.
Okay, so he said, I
am in love with you.
I'm in love with you in love.
Okay, so what's the
difference between two love
and to be in love? To
be in love with someone
means that you have these strong romantic
feelings towards somebody. That's right. So
you can only be in
love with your boyfriend,
your girlfriend, your
husband, or your wife.
So you can love your
parents. You can love your
family, but you can
be in love with them.
You can only be in
love with your girlfriend,
boyfriend, husband,
wife. That's right. Okay.
So moving on to the next phrase. Now
the girl asked her boyfriend, can we talk?
Can we talk? Can we talk?
This is a very simple sentence.
Right, we know
the meaning, right?
But why does she
say can we talk?
Okay, so you use this when
you want to start a conversation
about something serious. Okay, so if you
wanted to talk to me about my new shirt,
I wouldn't ask, I wouldn't say, hey, Marco,
can we talk? Oh, I really like your shirt.
Where'd you get
it? Exactly, right?
So it has to be serious. So usually,
if somebody says, hey, can we talk?
It means that there's
going to be a serious topic.
It's going to be
probably bad news.
Maybe that. So can we talk?
So if your boyfriend or
girlfriend tells you this, well,
it's not a good sign.
That's right. All right.
And the last phrase
that we have on fluency
builder, you know what I
mean. You know what I mean.
You know what I mean.
All right. So again, this phrase is very
simple to understand, right? That's right.
So you know what
I'm talking about.
You understand me. But
the interesting thing is that
we can also make it a question.
And it's all about the change in tone.
Okay. So with this in
mind, let's listen to two
examples of the same
phrase, but with different
tones, and you try to see which
one is the question. Example one.
I'm tired of doing nothing all day
here at home. You know what I mean?
Example two. Come on,
Charles. You know what I
mean when I say that I
don't like your friends?
Example three. I hate this class. It's so
boring and tedious. You know what I mean?
All right. So we
heard the examples.
And well, maybe you guessed
it right. The second example
was the question. That's
right. You know what I mean?
Right. So basically,
you're asking the person
if they understand your
idea or they understand
what you're talking about.
So maybe you can say,
so the professor wasn't
very clear on his instructions.
So how was I supposed
to do the homework?
You know what I mean? So
you're asking me to confirm
that I understand you
my idea. You understand
what I'm saying? Yeah.
Okay. And if it was a
statement, I might say,
hey, I don't like going to
your mom's house.
So I would say what?
What do you mean? Why?
You know what I mean? Right.
So I perfectly understand
or know the reasons why you
don't like going to my mom's.
Like, I don't have to tell you.
You know what I mean. All right.
Very good. So you
know what I mean. Great.
So we've taken a look
at these four phrases.
They're very simple. But the
way that you use them gives them
different meanings.
That's right. All right.
So let's listen to our
dialogue for the second time.
Let's slow it down a little bit.
And then we'll come back
and look at some more phrases.
Can we talk? Sure, honey.
We're talking now, aren't we?
You know what I
mean. Yeah, I know.
I want to know where
this relationship is going.
I mean, love with you.
And I need to know.
You know, I think you're
awesome. I'm awesome.
Well, I guess that's my
answer, isn't it? Honey.
Look, if you don't
love me, it's not a thing.
All right. We've had our
laughs, but I don't appreciate
well, maybe it's just time
we. Baby, I love you so much.
You do. I love you. And
I think you're awesome.
Oh, I love you too. Come on. Put
the gun down. Oh, baby. I'm so sorry.
Okay, so now it's time
for us to take a look at
some more phrases, but
this time we're going to look
at them in putting it
together. Putting it together.
Okay, we're going to see how we can use
these phrases in a few different situations.
So the girl wanted to talk
to her boyfriend because she
wanted to know where this
relationship is going, right?
Where is this
relationship going?
Where is this relationship
going? So she wants to
know what's going to
happen or what's the future?
What's the future
of this relationship?
Are we going to get
married or what's happening?
Yep. So why don't we
listen to some examples with
different nouns and how
we can use this phrase?
Example one. I don't
know where my career is
going in this company.
I don't see any potential
for growth. Example two.
This movie is so confusing.
I have no idea where
the plot is going.
Example three. We have
been in this meeting for
over two hours and I still
don't know where it's going.
Okay, so again, this phrase is just asking
about the future of something. Right.
So where the future of this
movie, where is this movie going?
Yeah, what's happening?
Right. What's going to happen?
Yeah. Or your career,
etc. Yeah. Okay.
And so the girl, you know,
she was talking a little
bit about her feelings and
she said, maybe it's just time we.
Okay. So this phrase
isn't complete yet.
Yeah. We need
to finish it. Yeah.
But she is basically saying,
maybe we should do this.
How can we finish
the phrase? All right.
So so she could say, maybe
it's just time we break up.
All right. Or I can say, maybe it's
time we have a baby. Oh, Marco.
All right. Even maybe
it's time we go home.
Okay. So it's getting
late. Let's go home.
Maybe it's time we go home.
Yeah. So this is how we can
finish this phrase. And
what about our last phrase?
So she also said, we've
had our laps. Okay.
So that means we've had
our good times. Yep. Okay.
But we can change this to we've had our ups
and downs. Okay. Or we've had our moments.
Right. So that means we've had our good
moments and our bad moments. That's right.
Or we've had our issues.
Okay. So that means we've
had some problem.
We've had some difficulties.
Or even we've had our
moments. Okay. So that means
we've had special times,
special occasions that
we will always remember.
That's right. Okay.
So a really useful
structure is that you can
change the words a little bit
to slightly change the meaning.
Okay. So it's time
for us to listen
to our dialogue for the
last time. Now we're ready
to understand everything.
And then we'll come
back and give you some
examples of pet names in English.
Can we talk? Sure, honey.
We're talking now, aren't we?
You know what I
mean. Yeah, I know.
I want to know where
this relationship is going.
I'm in love with you
and I need to know.
You know, I think you're
awesome. I'm awesome.
Well, I guess that's my
answer, isn't it? Honey.
Look, if you don't love
me, it's not a thing. All right.
We've had our laps, but
I don't appreciate well,
maybe it's just time we.
Baby, I love you so much.
You do? I love you and
I think you're awesome.
Oh, I love you too. Come
on, put the gun down.
Oh, baby, I'm so sorry.
All right, O Marco, you
mentioned this word pet names.
Um, and what exactly
is that? All right, so
pet names aren't names for
your dogs or your cats, right?
Right. They are those sweet names that you
would call your boyfriend or girlfriend.
Okay, so like, baby. Okay, in
our dialogue, we heard baby.
Yep. Right. So we're not talking
about a little, a little child now.
This is usually how you
would call maybe your girlfriend
or boyfriend, baby,
or honey, honey, right?
Hey, honey, or honey,
I'm home. Yeah. Right.
But we also have other ones
like sweetheart or darling,
darling, or what about
sweetie or cutie? Cutie.
Oh, so some of these
phrases can be a little bit
like cheesy, maybe like,
yeah, a little too, too much.
Smuckums, snuckums,
snuckums, likes snuckums.
Okay, or honey bunny.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
You also have sweetie pie.
Yeah. And some, some of them
will, will make some
up, right? Maybe they'll
call their, their boyfriend,
um, poo bear. Oh, yeah.
Right? Yeah. Like, you know, like, we
need a poo bear. Yeah. I heard dumpling.
Also, it could be, you
can make up your own for
it. You can make up your
own pet names, right?
Yeah. So I want to
hear from our listeners.
Are there any common
pet names in your language?
I know that in Spanish,
we sometimes call
the, we, we can sometimes
call our girlfriend,
which actually means fat, but
it's not in a bad way. Really?
It's a sweet way of calling
your, your, your, your girlfriend.
And I know in French,
you can say, my poo switch
basically means my flea.
Yeah. So some of them,
if you translate, you
wouldn't really use in
English, but let us know
translate from your language
or other ones that
you've heard maybe in
movies or talk shows and
come to our website, EnglishPod.
com. Yep. Leave your
questions there as
well as your pet names
and Marco and I are always
happy to see you there. Okay.
Until next time, goodbye. Bye.